Finding Aid for the Joseph E. Wright Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Joseph E. Wright Papers
1931-1968
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0532
1.26 linear_feet
Biography
Joseph E. Wright (1918-) was born in Memphis, Tennessee. He received is B.S. from Memphis State College in 1938; his M.A. from Northwestern University in 1946; and completed additional graduate work at Columbia University. He served in the military during World War II. During his life he produced plays for highschool and college students, adults, and military personnel. Joseph Wright began his employment with Vanderbilt University in 1946 as Assistant Professor of Dramatics and Public Speaking. In addition to his teaching duties in dramatic literature, he served as Director of the Vanderbilt University Theatre. He retired in 1986.
This collection was donated by Joseph E. Wright.
Scope and Contents
This one linear foot collection contains five series in 38 file folders:
Series I contains ephemeral items related to George Bernard Shaw
Series II contains incoming correspondence from a teacher and her class who attended a production of Hamlet
Series III contains a poem written by Donald Davidson to the cast of the first Singin Billy production
Series IV contains prompt books for plays
Series V contains theatre programs.
- Series I – George Bernard Shaw
  - Correspondence – Outgoing
    - re: Lowke Domestic Engineering Company, February 9, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - note card, February 10, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - re: Lowke Domestic Engineering Company, February 12, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Contracts and Deeds
    - Deed of Arrangement between Harold Austin Bassett Lowke and his Creditors, February 10, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Authority signed by Creditors for Dividend, September 20, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series II – Correspondence - Incoming
  - From a Teacher and her Students
    - Lynn Hewes – teacher, March 6, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Phil Cannady, March 7, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Elaine Crockett, March 3, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Betty Ann Cullipher, March 7, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Brenda Estes, March 7, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Anna Felts, March 6, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Cheryl Finley, March 3, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Mary Frye, March 6, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Marcia Fly, March 7, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Susan Futrell, March 7, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Jerald Garnett, March 3, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Jane Hunter, March 7, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Margaret Jones, March 3, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Carol Lyles, March 6, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Linda McCool, March 6, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Cheryl McDow, March 5, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Pam Miller, March 7, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Poole, March 7, 1961
    - Judy Saeger, March 3, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Warren Schultz, March 3, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Paula Singleton, March 3, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Connie Smith, March 7, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Larry Stanley, March 6, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Timothy Walker, March 6, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - William Wall, March 6, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Kitty White, March 6, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Series III – Poem
    - To the Fair and Brave, by Donald Davidson Sent to the cast of the first Singin Billy Production, Vanderbilt Theatre, Nashville April, 23-28, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Series IV – Prompt Books
    - Arsenic and Old Lace (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - The Barber of Seville (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - The Conversion of Buster Drumwright (Folder 11)
    - The Doctor in Spite of Himself (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Founders’ Capers (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - The Ghosts (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Hamlet (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Julius Caesar (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Juno and the Paycock (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - King Lear (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - The Love of Four Colonels (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - The Marching Song (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Measure for Measure (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - The Merchant of Venice (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - The Miser (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Much Ado About Nothing (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Much Ado About Nothing [second copy] (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Oedipus Rex (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Othello (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Othello [continued] (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Othello [continued] (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Playboy of the Western World (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - The Silver Cord (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Strangers in this World (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Strangers in this World [second copy]-copyright granted, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - The Taming of the Shrew (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Twelfth Night (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Warn Lights (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Oversized Materials - Series V – Theatre Programs – Ford’s Theatre
    - John Brown’s Body, February 12, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - The Comedy of Errors, February 26, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - She Stoops To Conquer, March 26, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 38)